

# Nishanth artham

WEB DEVELOPER

- 1-7-1/50/2, NEW REDDY ENCLAVE, TEMPLE ALWAL, HYDERABAD, TELANGANA
- arthamnishanth123@gmail.com
- +91 90591 05727
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/nishanth -artham-1a572b212/

#### **PROFILE**

I am Nishanth. I am pursuing my bachelor's degree in CBIT, Hyderabad. I am passionate about gaining knowledge on new skills and exploring my capabilities. I am comfortable with web development and GUI (Graphical User Interface) using Python. I worked on my mini-project, which helped me to examine and enhance my skills in Python as well as in Web-development.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **DESIGN INTERN**

## Interviews Master

Feb 2022 - Mar 2022

- Developed UI design for the interview masters website
- Worked on LearnWorlds Platform

#### WEB DEVELOPER INTERN

# **Zummit Infolabs**

Oct 2021 - Jan 2022

- Developed many front end web pages using react and other tools
- Created Figma designs, prototypes to develop the webpage
- Created a react page that consumes JSON data coming from a URL and displays it on the webpage Presented the project work to clients and implemented their ideas successfully.
- Used PHP to fix backend bugs

#### CO-FOUNDER AND INSTRUCTOR

# **EdSpread**

Aug 2021 - Nov 2021

- As an Instructor at Edspread you get to tutor trending technologies with a 7-day Boot-camp and thereby completing a real-time project
- I tutored the entire Web-Development course in Edspread which includes HTML, CSS, Javascript and react.js

## **EDUCATION HISTORY**

#### BE in

# Information Technology

Nov 2020 -Mar 2024

# Chaitanya Bharathi Institute Of Technology

- Achieved 2nd position from the entire IT department with an SGPA of 9.9
- Current CGPA is 9.77

# SKILLS

- Languages –
   C,Python(Tkinter),Java
   (Networking,databases,JSP,servlets), Javascript
- Frontend HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery
- Frontend Frameworks –
  React.js, BootStrap
- Backend Languages PHP, Java
- Backend frameworks Spring, nest.js
- Databases MySQL, Oracle SQL, MongoDB
- Other JSON, API, git, Data Structures, Object-Oriented Programming, Unix commands

## **EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

## Member of UC3 Coding club Feb 2022 - Present

- Generate new coding questions
- Conducted coding competitions
- Participated in Doubt-Clearing sessions to discuss solutions for coding problems

#### Hack Revolution 2022

Jan 2022

- Qualifiers of Hack Revolution hackathon
- Created the front-end part of the website
- Designed tables in the database

## **PROJECTS**

## Student Management - HRMS project containing Student data

 A project which records and stores Student Information in a database along with CRUD operations - PHP, MYSQL, HTML, CSS

# Language Translator - API based GUI application

 A google trans API which translates the given text in a language to 108 different languages with a single button click - Python(Tkinter)

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Certificate for Python (Issued by: Hacker Rank)
- Certificate for Cloud Computing (Issued by: NPTEL)
- Certificate for Problem Solving (Issued by: Hacker Rank)
- Certificate for SQL Intermediate (Issued by: Hacker Rank)
- Certificate for SQL Basic (Issued by: Hacker Rank)